welcome to Diamond Mountain it's very
exciting to see friends from many many
countries it's kind of strange to see
you here
in the desert especially Singaporeans it
doesn't rain here okay there's no
Orchard Road and but it's beautiful to
see here mr. moon welcome from Guangzhou
yeah Yali from Taiwan has been avoiding
coming here she and her group have been
a big supporter of ACI and we love you
and everyone there's many many countries
many people thank you for coming we have
a busy night so I won't talk too much
which is unusual we're gonna do the
first-class ACI in number 3 it's the
earphones work okay
how much okay and then we'll so we'll do
the first class of a CI number three and
then we'll do lama chiba lama chiba is
probably the most famous prayer in tibet
I remember the first time I met Tibetans
I walked into a lama cello by accident
and it was you know amazing and so we're
gonna do this special prayer it's a it's
a long prayer the poetry is very
beautiful it's very old maybe we should
rewrite it I don't know but the main
thing is to think about all your
teachers in your life okay and we're all
very very lucky you're still alive you
can still walk you had beautiful parents
who taught you to speak how to dress how
to not bite other people
and we don't think about it but your
parents taught you many many things your
first teachers and then in the school
people taught you how to read without
reading you would be like a blind person
and and they taught you how to behave we
didn't like those teachers but they were
good and then we had our later our
college teachers and we had religious
teachers many of us our whole life
priests or rabbis or Imams so we are
lucky that we've had such beautiful
teachers and their prayer tonight is to
honor all the teachers in your life one
man told me his dog was his teacher
that's okay
my dog taught me a lot so it could be
your dog okay I think the most important
teacher is the people you don't like and
they help you practice Buddhism just
imagine if everybody was very sweet you
you couldn't practice anything so we are
lucky to have all these teachers okay so
tonight we will honor them and it's a
long prayer and there's a lot of
complicated things and don't worry much
about it okay
just keep that mood then you wouldn't be
here without your parents and your other
teachers we are really very lucky we are
all very very lucky I had great teachers
too much I still have great teachers so
we are lucky so think about your
teachers that's how we start a retreat
at Diamond Mountain we always do the
prayer to the teachers okay and it's
always a good thing to do when you start
something important okay during that
prayer we handouts all talk means it's
an emptiness meditation they will hand
you a glass of I don't know what it is
alcohol don't drink the whole thing
that's not allowed for Buddhists but its
traditional to take one left-hand third
finger take one drop and put it on your
tongue then there's a small dish if we
call Bala special substance and you can
take one piece and bind a half and keep
okay if you if you don't understand why
to do it and you don't feel like doing
it you don't have to okay but it's meat
and the other is alcohol we make a
special prayer during the Lama Chapa we
pray that these things are not available
in the world in the future like right
now if even in Arizona if you go to buy
a human finger they will not sell to you
but they will tell you everyone else's
finger then I think in the future nobody
will sell anybody's fingers you know so
we make a prayer that these things that
shouldn't exist in the future alcohol
killed my mother killed my father and
it's a terrible stupid thing like
marijuana and it will hurt you for the
rest of your lives so we take it we take
those two things and we think about a
prayer that we wish these things will
not be sold anywhere in the future okay
they're gonna give you a cookie the
cookie is good to eat I will take three
or four just kidding but these three
items they represent thinking about
emptiness all things have emptiness
terrible things have emptiness like meat
or alcohol sweet things have emptiness
cookies they all have emptiness in one
way all things have the same thing are
the same thing okay that doesn't mean
you can do bad things okay it just means
everything has its own emptiness we will
talk about it okay
then I guess I hope there's some musical
Tim is there music no yeah okay no music
and so we'll have that prayer so first
I'll teach the class and because after
the prayer we invite you to eat all the
offerings and no one will pay attention
to the class so we do the class first
then you get the refreshments okay all
right so we are studying this retreat is
divided into two parts one is the
Gardner training you have jet lag I
don't she's showing her her dentist just
kidding but it's it's nice that you have
jet lag and I don't it never happens
so first we'll be studying are you in
The Guardian a very very very famous
mother book of all emptiness teachings
it's the most important book of
emptiness ever written and we've been
going through a commentary it's going to
take five years this is the second year
okay so we will do it five times and
it's an amazing text very very difficult
extremely difficult and so I like hard
things except Charles should be soft but
I write mostly but it's a beautiful
beautiful text and we're gonna go very
deep into it okay so you're lucky to be
here very few people have gotten that
teaching and then secondly in the
evenings will be doing the ACI teacher
training we are training people to be
teachers ACI and you're welcome to
participate in that training if you like
okay
you don't have to if you'd rather
meditate in your cabin in the evening
that's also very good okay but if you'd
like to be an ACI teacher you can join
that teacher training just talk to Tim
about if you didn't sign up already
we're going to be covering Asian
classics Institute course number three
there are 36 courses of ACI there are 18
open courses and there are 18 secret
courses and it took about 12 or 13 years
to teach it the first time I started in
New York in 1936 and the whole course
took about 14 years and we transferred
the first 18 courses are the Geisha
course okay it's the essence of the
Geisha course so of course we do much
deeper in the monastery but if you study
the 18 the first 18 ACI courses then we
can say you have studied all the
subjects that are Getty studies okay we
call baby gishy and then the 18 diamond
way courses faggiano
these are advanced Buddhism for people
who would like to become enlightened in
one lifetime and those we taught here
when we first started Diamond Mountain
it took seven years it's about I don't
know how many pages jing-mei do you know
how many pages of translation I don't
know ten thousand something think that
it's about ten thousand pages of the
high secret teachings and I think it's
the first time that they were organized
into a really clear course in history so
it's an amazing course and if you have
time it would be nice to to learn it
okay
Yuki you have to finish the first 18
courses before you can do the second 18
courses and don't ask
to do the second 18 courses before you
do the first 18 courses because that's
like driving a car without ever
practicing driving your car and there
will be a crash okay understand so
finish the first 18 courses and then
negotiate with John Brady or Jake May or
other people an autonomous okay so we
are studying course number three of the
open courses and that's called applied
meditation when I first designed the
course which is probably around 1992 or
something
before you were born Jenny and I wanted
some kind of meditation that people
could do at home and at work you know I
wanted some kind of meditation that
people could do it business at the time
people thought either you're a business
person or you're a family person or
you're a meditator in a cave you know so
that was the three choices and I felt
very strongly that we should unify
people's family life and their
meditation life and this was an ancient
custom in India about a thousand years
ago and the most successful meditators
were the politicians and the very
leading business people and Buddha
taught Vajrayana for them like the color
chakra but Diamond Way was thought
originally for Kings only for kings and
busy people business business people so
I felt strongly then people used to ask
me you want to be a business person or
you want to be a meditator and I said
well I want to be both you know I want
to be successful in in my life and I
want to be successful inside I don't
want to choose between those two so I
called the course applied meditation
applied means you don't just meditate in
a cave or in your house you use it at
work and you use it on your husband when
he's bad
okay so this is applied meditation
something you can use in your real life
so that's the name of the course course
number three because it's a teacher
training every night when I teach this
course and we will finish the course
this week these nine days I think we'll
finish that course so you might as well
get certified then you can teach it to
people you know legally there's a lot of
illegal teachers that's okay but they
make mistakes so anyway we're gonna go
through that every every night and I'll
teach you how to teach it you see what I
mean so I'm not just teaching you the
course I'd like to add my comments about
how to teach it because that's also
important and it's not the same as it's
not the same as taking the course as
teaching it okay Shuchi knows from
teaching computers yes how many people
in your class mm just 500 just 900 he
teaches computers in Singapore he tried
to teach me but it was hopeless again
some different teaching it and knowing
right so let's learn how to teach it
okay I'm gonna be going to your homework
because the first night I have to sort
of I have to actually talk about the
subject and not tell stories that I
enjoy so let's go to the actual subject
okay we're gonna go through homework
number one there's Rob Russell who who's
the king of dynamo
[Music]
he squeezed his money from rocks and
keeps the place going god bless you okay
hmm so our study I'm gonna go through
the homework with you okay and talk
about teaching it we're gonna study
meditation the first thing I'd like to
say is the course is designed in five
major steps okay there are five major
parts to the study of meditation those
of you who have taken DCI course level
three is it it's the same you've learned
a lot of this already but in this case
it's more religious content okay using
it formulating okay so first subject of
the five is will study how to get ready
for a meditation what are the practical
how to set up your room how to set up
your altar how to set up your seat
things like that okay and that's an
important step in meditation is to
create a beautiful space for meditation
in your home and I've been to people's
homes in in New York City
and they're tiny tiny apartments even
that is extremely expensive in New York
more expensive in Hong Kong Singapore
but they the people have a screen
Japanese screen and it behind that it
looks like a temple you know so the
apartment looks like it has three kids
and because it does and but the corner
is very beautiful and very peaceful when
you just peek behind the screen you feel
already you feel very peaceful okay so
it's a we're gonna talk about how to
create a sacred space in your house the
biggest job of a meditation teacher okay
the most difficult job of a meditation
teacher is one to get people to meditate
now it's almost impossible I've been
trying for 45 years it's almost
impossible I have a new trick okay I'll
tell you right now it's a good night to
tell you okay if you don't remember
anything from this course remember this
and we developed it in DCI for ten years
and now when we teach people to meditate
the first thing we say is don't meditate
for too long you will quit okay because
you are busy you're busy people okay you
don't get paid to meditate no one's
gonna give you a raise you know your
wife or husband is gonna be irritated by
humility so how to find time to meditate
okay this is the big big big thing about
a meditation teacher it doesn't matter
that you have 200 meditations from 2,000
years ago which we do it doesn't matter
it's just time trying to get people to
spend the time to meditate and it's
almost impossible so here's a new trick
that we use in DCI I think an ACI
teacher should use it tell people look
and I did a three-year retreat not far
from here in the desert and it was hard
in one room extremely difficult hot cold
lots of strange animals one night we had
seven rattlesnakes inside the yurt area
seven you know deadly you know and it
was hard and very hard and I learned
something in 1,000 days of meditation
you cannot meditate more than three
hours in a day I don't care who you are
so the other you know 15 hours we used
to just we learned to sew
triangle I'm not the talk we didn't talk
we were tough we didn't talk for three
years and so anyway three hours of good
meditation it's very very difficult and
there are many people in the room who've
done through your routine and they can
tell you okay so what we encourage
people just meditate for 10 minutes a
day okay you want to be a a CI teacher
you want to be a a CI meditation teacher
learn to say that sentence just meditate
for 10 minutes a day don't try to do
more you will quit you will certainly
quit within three weeks you will quit
okay I don't care who you are you will
quit okay everybody's busy okay and that
phone that this internet that was
supposed to save you time is now
stealing all of your time nobody has any
time I know this very brilliant man
in my neighborhood he discovered the
atmosphere of Pluto recently he's a
brilliant astronomer very famous and he
owned the cafe and so I've got to know
him but he refuses to have a cell phone
okay and he's one of the greatest
astronomers in the world and he refuses
to have a cell phone
he's I need my time I refused it I won't
have that you know it's very strange
okay anyway get people to meditate for
10 minutes then say look every Sunday or
whatever is your day off the Israelis
told me it's not Sunday - like it's
Saturday
ok Saturday or wherever you live your
day are increase it one minute ok so
next week you're doing 11 minutes and
the next week you're doing 12 minutes
and you won't feel it you
used to it okay it doesn't feel ten
minutes come on you poop longer than ten
minutes everyday you know you can do ten
minutes to get enlightened the other
thing is just a waste of time okay so
one more minute every week and you you
won't notice it it's a trick okay it's a
very good trick because in one year
there will be meditating one hour and
two minutes okay and you need one hour
to see emptiness you need one hour to
see emptiness the only thing you have to
do in this life is to see emptiness
directly the rest is dessert okay the
only thing you have to do in this life
is to see emptiness directly then
everything is taken care of for this
life and forever lives just twenty
minutes okay but you can't do it if you
don't meditate for an hour every day so
trick yourself okay if it takes a year
to get to one hour that's fine you will
you'll be strong you'll be a good
meditator like if you try to lift 200
pounds the first day you will break your
head and then you were quick just do
five pounds then do six pounds the guy
who taught me to do yoga in my
three-year retreat we had a special
teacher come twice a year very famous
yoga teacher David Swensen he said okay
can I touch your toes he could talk we
couldn't talk he touch your toes I
touched my knees you know he said go
lower I said I can't I can't do it so he
the next day he came into the retreat
Kevin with a ten phone book telephone
books old telephone books before
internet okay and they had very thin
pages and he had ten telephone books he
said he put them on top of each other he
said touch the top one I'm like I can do
that he said okay tomorrow
rip out one page okay then you know it
took like three years to finish the last
phonebook but I did it okay and you can
do if you learn to meditate like that
okay so as a meditation teacher the most
important thing to teach your students
don't try to meditate too long you
acquit okay if a new person meditates
for more than ten minutes they are
thinking about nothing and they are
wasting their time okay
nobody can meditate for an hour without
years of training not possible okay
forget it if they sit there for three
hours trust me they're thinking about yo
chousen should are some punches okay
right trust me they are I don't care how
they look on the outside they're not
meditating trust me okay I did it for
two years I know it's not possible it's
all the faith give me ten good minutes
then give me eleven good minutes okay so
when you teach it that's the most
important thing you have to do how to
get people on their cushion it's the big
fight okay my yoga teacher said look
roll out the mat get on touch it
roll out the mat and touch it then
you're gonna do yoga every day just roll
out the mat and touch it then you'll do
yoga
just put the buck on the cushion the bud
has to touch the cushion only once I got
I rolled out the mat I stood on it and
then I rolled it back up and I had a big
breakfast that's how you know so you
know just make contact the P go and the
meditation cushion
okay then you're okay then you okay okay
okay okay first how to prepare for
meditation second there are six
conditions for an ideal meditation
environment so you have to set up your
meditation environment okay that's
number two number three there's a
correct posture for meditation it has
eight details and it was taught
originally connected to vital China
which is a special meditation Buddha
okay vital China's main quality is the
ability to appear in whatever way that
makes people comfortable
okay so vital China maybe look like a
rock and roll star right Stanley ding
ding ding ding ding ding right made a
and so that's about China's special
ability is to look anyway it's
comfortable for people okay like these
guys or change the outfit for a
different audience okay sometimes a suit
extremely uncomfortable
okay what's the two worst business karma
tie and high-heeled shoes these are the
two worst business karma okay okay
that's number three a correct posture
number four how do you control your mind
during meditation okay what is the
mental process during meditation okay
that's the fourth thing we're gonna
study how to keep the mind in meditation
okay fifth thing which sometimes
meditation teachers don't talk about is
what are you gonna meditate huh the
object of your meditation so it's not
true and by the way as a meditation
teacher
the biggest war you have to fight is to
get the student too many thin
okay and not too long that
second-hardest war you have to fight
it's against all the stupid meditation
being taught in yoga studios around the
world okay people are teaching really
really dumb meditation mainly try to
think about nothing okay
whenever you see meditation in the
movies
the guys I try to think about nothing
okay and that's the worst meditation you
can do okay that's worse than not
meditating okay so you're gonna have to
fight against what you call a huge river
of like flood of the Yangtze River and
you're one person try to stop the river
it's gonna be a challenge okay people
think meditation means close your eyes
and think about nothing and people right
now all over the world are teaching done
tonight I'm sure somewhere and you have
to fight that meditation has an object
meditation has many objects you have to
choose the object you have to learn to
stay on the object that's meditation
okay and there are many kinds of objects
and you have to learn what are the most
powerful okay and so you're your home
meditation career as a teacher of
meditation you're gonna have to fight
against this wrong idea of thinking
about nothing okay
by the way the karmic result of thinking
about nothing is just that okay and you
become kind of forgetful okay you can't
remember things if you try to meditate
about nothing for a year or two you
become the person who is you know they
lost my phone dance
well where'd I leave if you meditate
about nothing the Karma's that you will
become you'll become a phone loser
person okay seriously it's very famous
in the scriptures but people don't know
okay so those are the five subjects
we're gonna study in our study of
meditation now I'd like to introduce to
you some words famous ancient words
about meditation for two reasons number
one each one gives a different flavor of
what meditation is number two you can
impress your student if you have a lot
of foreign words especially sense okay
the first time I said that in his
commentary learned some Sanskrit so you
can impress your students trust me it
worse okay okay so I'm going to teach
you how many words one I'm going to
teach you five sorry six important words
for meditation
okay each one has a slightly different
flavor okay here's the first one and I'm
gonna give you the Tibetan first say
gamba gamba okay there's a Tibetan word
that means monastery they call gamba
that's not this word this is a different
one gamba means to meditate okay the
Sanskrit for gamba is BA homina homina
[Music]
okay Bhavana yeah bhava means to be and
the word to be comes from other means
makes make her like plumber teacher
talker okay procrastinator
so honor means earth in in Sanskrit
bhava means to become so brahmana means
you repeat a mental picture over and
over and over and over and then it you
will become that thing okay you repeat a
mental picture over and over and over
and then you will become that thing so
if you talk about meditation objects a
good one for banana would be a Buddha
okay just keep thinking about them you
know just keep bringing them into your
mind and your mind will get used to it
and then you will become that thing okay
you will become that thing which you
daydream about all the time okay and you
will become nothing that's the flavor of
the domina meditation they're all can be
translated as meditation but this one
means makes you become ER it makes you
become ER
okay it says mental process which makes
you turn into something okay that you
weren't okay second one say something
something the sanskrit here is you can
say tiana I think you know but the word
dianna used to be pronounced Gianna in
in ancient India and then when it came
to China they said it Chan Chan and when
it moved to Japan Gianna became Chen
Zhen so this Zen comes from the word
Jana okay Gianna means meditation okay
it's another kind of meditation we're
gonna be studying a special meditation
called the lion stance there
the first four levels that we do are all
called something so Deanna
Gianni level beyond another level of
meditation okay you can say that the
emphasis of Gianna is the ability to
hold the mind on a single object we call
a car girl okay say a Kagura eka means
one like a protein gel polish structure
this is Indian language okay I come into
one have some friends a cuyana
right one path the accumbens one other
means a tip so a Kagura means the single
pointed mind so Deanna emphasis of the
meaning of the word is that you can keep
your mind on a single object single
point single pointed and single object
in English we say the guy is very single
pointed one he just thinks about his
business he doesn't think about his wife
his kids anything else he's single
pointed mine okay and and it's a kind of
meditation single point means you are
able to hold your mind on a single
object without moving okay without
thinking about other things I was taught
meditation my first meditation teacher
was going kheh he's from Burma a
businessman from Burma and he invented
the personal okay and he was my first
meditation teacher and he is to talk
about when he when he first came in - it
would be a 10-day retreat and you can't
speak for ten days you can't go anywhere
for ten days and he would say the first
thing he say every time he say ok I want
to talk to you about meditation okay
first thing during these 10 days don't
think about monkeys don't think about
monkeys then for 10 days we're like why
you see don't think about monkey
what's he mean don't think about monkey
then he's playing with us but it was
very cruel because ten days that we can
only think about monkeys okay it means
that don't don't think about monkeys now
you're gonna think about monkeys all
week when you meditate choose one object
stay on that aunty okay I hate that
Russian thing by the way it was a very
good introduction to meditation but I I
wouldn't I wouldn't encourage people to
do bleep asana if you have other kinds
of man if you have learn more important
kinds of meditation I wouldn't get stuck
watching your breath okay
that's a not a very important object
okay alright you can learn much deeper
objects here okay and but I understand
the other system and I like it I enjoyed
it and I learned a lot but I wouldn't I
wouldn't encourage you to do it you you
have higher places to go and you don't
have time you don't have much time okay
alright
mmm the Tibetan is something okay now
third one in Tibetan is called yum juice
a gnome do yo means equal like scale
right two pounds of gold and two pounds
of potatoes
it means equal okay Juke means stay stay
equal so it's another word for for
meditation okay I think I have them and
summer party it means stay in a balance
between two things
anybody know thinking about too busy and
jet lag too sleepy okay then these are
the two extremes your mind is too busy
thinking about too many things and then
over here is
you know getting sleepy so by the way in
my opinion Namjoo
summer party is very very good for
business people okay like any kind of
business all right
people say you could learn to meditate
or you could be a business person I say
both you know be successful in your life
why not you can help more people I've
bought a restaurant this guy say you
want to buy my restaurant you yeah okay
cuz he takes a lot of takes care of a
lot of poor people you know and then
we're gonna make Thanksgiving dinner for
all the poor people for free we're gonna
lose money and and thatthat stuffs
astronomer guy who just discovered the
atmosphere of a planet he works for the
observatory which discovered Pluto and
he discovered the atmosphere Pluto
recently okay and he's amazing and he
runs a restaurant you see some half the
day he's discovering planets and had two
day he's therming coffee
but the way he serves coffee it's
amazing to watch him you know he's
extremely happy his mind is well
balanced his life is well balanced
mental life is beautiful to watch and
how gracefully he he pours the coffee
it's like the tea ceremony in China or
Japan if if someone really knows how to
do it
this is meditation you know and he's
like pouring coffee with total focus not
sleepy and not busy just focus on the
customer and the coffee you know and
it's so he's so elegant and he's 75 and
he
you know and his mic
I guess he's thinking about he's
tracking 2300 asteroids that might hit
the earth it's one of his jobs he
figured out how to measure them you know
so his buddies pouring coffee you see I
mean so that's kind of some uppity okay
youngdo balanced state of mind not busy
and not bored focus okay so for me that
one is more see each word has a
different flavor in the in the sanskrit
we are balanced between too busy and too
sleepy we are in that rare focused state
of mind pouring the coffee for the
people okay alright next one is called
young shark saying young shark i I lost
the sense can summer heat I think so
mijita and this is the one that's often
related to the direct perception of
emptiness
okay the flavor is again it's balanced
meditation summer kita but it means on a
high object sometimes it's called
cessation meditation because in this
meditation you can stop all negative
states of mind you can stop the ultimate
negative states of mind in this
meditations there are words for
meditation you can use them for
meditation all of them in I heard in in
Eskimo language they have 17 words for
the color of white snow and Peru ski yes
Lucia story did not slow de la Tommy him
show me a Ghana is not a pharisee state
sector it your doors
[Music]
thanks in Russian they have this word
for dark sky it's always snowing cold
and dark in Singapore there must be 24
words for jungle ring yeah yeah okay so
anyway if you're thinking about
meditation all the time there's six
different words and they all have
different flavours it's a good sign that
when a language has six different
flavors of words for meditation okay
it's a good sign
all right next one Cassini this is
schemata okay schemata and the word sham
means peace in you're in a yoga class
you say Shanti Shanti Shanti that's the
same root okay the ancient world is
really shot Chris Shanti Shanti and that
came to be the word for patience because
you have a peaceful mind and all K s HS
in Sanskrit came into English as qu i qu
uh quiet calm quiet - okay all these
words come from some schemata it means
peaceful mind so the emphasis there is
on a peaceful mind like a calm lake or
pond calm water okay super super calm
water of a lake without any wind in the
morning this is like schemata and the
idea is that if your mind is calm enough
without ripples you can see emptiness
directly emptiness can reflect in the
mirror of your mind but only if it's
perfect calm perfect complement
okay so schemata means perfect calm mind
that you used to see emptiness okay it's
always it's a twin
okay Gemini it's always joined with the
past Vipassana they say be pacchiana
okay that's the real word Vipassana is a
corruption okay it's like how you doing
man
I do man what's up what's up man I do
okay the Pastner okay the world is
Vipassana and pashya means to see the
means is super well
super good okay it comes from the V
which means double and that's why the
English word too has W it came from the
be okay it means double strong double
deep V V means super super seeing okay
super C V passion okay so that's a what
is that five right shemitah okay I got
one more for you
here we go say things in things in the
fleet it's a Tibetan word the flavour is
vivid okay vivid and the way I learned
the word my teacher we were driving past
some rice fields and he said to me I
think it means super blue super green
thingy means I don't know like the
diamond amount in sky during the day
like we caught thing not thinking
thinking
it means super blue you know super blue
okay so thinking Zen means super I don't
know the whole mind is like the blue sky
super blue but it means a super-sweet
meditation okay pinging seems like when
you're listening to music that you
really like and you like
yeah that's thing in this and your mom
says or your wife says dinner's ready
and you're like you know that's thing is
them okay I don't know how you say the
mind is into the object the mind melts
into the object how's that so those are
six words for meditation each one has a
different flavor okay each one has a
different flavor okay all right now I'm
gonna talk about homework question
number three which is that's how I get
people to take notes Chinese take notes
anyway they probably take notes about my
jokes also but Westerners don't take any
notes anyway take notes
six preliminaries to a meditation saves
things you have to do before you start
to meditate okay six things you have to
do before you start to meditate number
one create a clean and sacred space with
an altar okay and it can be a small
table put a nice cloth on okay I feel
weird when I'm at home I spend about two
hours a day cookie when I'm cooking
dinner
it's like to our thing when I'm washing
the dishes it's like an hour or it feels
like three hours and then I think why
don't I spend this time on my altar you
know if you want to have good meditation
treat your altar like you treat your
stove or your refrigerator it's also
important you have three important
things in your house refrigerator stove
an altar and the altars the most
important thank you so try to give it
equal time you spend at least an hour a
day on the stone then spend some time on
the altar make it nice and change it
every day no Buddha wants to come to get
your three day old cookies or the fruit
is already spoiled the flower looks like
like make it pretty me you're trying to
attract these bees right these be the
bees then it should be pretty and and
fresh and beautiful to spend time on
your altar that's a sign of whether you
think meditation is important or not if
you have a nice altar if you if your
altars is dusty and the waters got green
stuff floating on you then it means
you're not very serious about your
meditation you know who wants to visit
what Buddha wants to visit when the
water bowls are full of green stuff
thank you and the flowers are like a
week old and okay they smell funny
all right so make it beautiful make it
attractive you're trying to attract
enlightened beings to your house so make
it nice okay spend time on you out there
make it sweet we spend more time on our
food than we do on our altar it should
be similar okay all right second every
morning put out some beautiful offerings
okay put out some beautiful offerings
there's a custom in Tibet to offer water
in a bowl maybe seven bowls eight balls
should be high-quality water by some
Perrier for your Buddhas
okay cheap ah sweet nice cheap possible
it's been tea and offer nice water to
your brew this they don't want to drink
on one
okay it's thinking winery okay all right
and something you love flowers so you
know I like cookies I like to put out
cookies I like turtles
yeowch I'll try to put a fresh okay all
right it's by the way it's a lot of fun
when you go to a restaurant buy buy an
extra dessert or buy an extra stuff and
put it in the middle of the table and
offer it to your Buddha they like it a
lot they really like one day we were in
DC I was in Sofia Bulgaria and we went
out and I think there were five of us
and we ordered six dinners and then the
lady said where is another person coming
we said yes and she said where should I
put you know we said put in the middle
and she looked at us and she said I know
what you do I really like it's just this
is for God right Arisa sweet things okay
don't give them chintzy when I call
tchotchkes cheap gifts they don't like
plastic flowers for example we had the
dynamic senior teacher Yamantaka came to
our temple and we put him on the throne
he was very old
he was very severe in a very great great
teacher of Tantra and then somebody put
plastic grapes on a dish next to him
and he was talking and he and I'm like
he's reaching for the grave and I'm like
anything
don't put plastic stuff on your altar it
was embarrassing okay I'm glad he
couldn't get it off okay step number
three hmm
goes through taking refuge go through
bodhichitta okay
go through those two sang a turn on song
any time I'm not I didn't know okay
[Music]
so we're supposed to take refuge
everyday right some bow something in the
three jewels but the real place to take
refuges in the kitchen who said wait
till I offer money yeah somebody said
you always talk about the kitchen talk
about Sutra I said everything the sutras
in the kitchen and everything in the
kitchens in the Sutra and if there's
something in the kitchen it's not the
series suddenly it's not the kitchen it
doesn't belong in a Citroen
because the Sutra was made for kitchen
the suit was made for people the Sutra
wasn't made for temples the suit was
made for real people if there's
something the Sutra you can use in the
kitchen that shouldn't be we should take
it out or change the kitchen
okay so refuge in the kitchen means my
husband's yelling at me because I yelled
at my kids that's all you just took
refuge
what is refuge me refuge means
protection why did you just protect
yourself
you didn't answer back harsh words to
your husband you didn't make
new bad karma because you remembered
about dependent origination with your
kids and the emptiness of the husband
who didn't come for me I didn't know
anything has been okay
you just took refuge okay go to a temple
save refuge ten thousand times wear out
your rosary it's not as good as using it
in the kitchen okay it's not no
comparison okay one minute in the
kitchen is worth three years in time'
mountains doing month really if you
understand then you took refuge you took
real refuge forget it that's okay then
body Tina I would like to get rid of my
anger in the kitchen so my sister can
get rid of her anger and then her uncle
can get rid of his anger and then his
friend can get rid of his anger I'm
gonna change the world by not getting up
standing in the kitchen okay that's
funny Tina forget all the rest
forget those sutras about body suffers
do it in the kitchen
that's funny something okay I'm gonna be
a good example for my children for my
friends okay for my husband all right so
anyway just before meditation think
about refuge think about buddy chip why
are you meditating what do you want
you're gonna die for sure you're gonna
die okay
you don't have time to fool around I
went to okay Tim part of the reason I
didn't do the reading on time I spent
much of the week I spent with my old
lady my old lady reached stage three
okay what stage three stage one is when
they take your car away Stage two is
when they take your house away and Stage
three is when they take away your Walker
and she just reached stage three it was
a very hard week okay now she will lie
down for the rest of them
I think I don't think she's gonna make
it back up so you don't have time okay
you don't have time don't mess around
okay do your meditation prepare think
about but do everything for body - okay
do everything for other people okay
don't waste your time doing things for
yourself is a waste of time
okay it's it's it's nothing it's
worthless
you can take it you know comb your hair
it's gonna fall out okay
even the girls gonna lose their hair
okay just takes longer okay trust me
okay
just stop taking care yourself take care
of other people then your life has some
meaning okay that's bunny to them okay
otherwise you're just wasting your time
and you will reach times three okay
reach stage three with bodhichitta then
you're okay alright number four before
you meditate fill up the room with holy
beans okay at least one at least your
teacher okay so I used to meditate in a
small room there wasn't space to get
more people in my room my teacher when I
went to meet him 1975 in January he said
I am a small tiny room for you it's for
the attendant you know you could touch
the walls like this he said don't worry
I'm gonna get you a better room soon
thirty years later I was feeling this
thing then there wasn't room to put all
the Buddha's in there so I used to put
them up on the ceiling I said you guys
stay up there there's no room
so put them in the room make them smile
just room for everybody so invite lots
of Buddhas make it a party okay they can
read your mind
they knew 1000 years ago that you were
going to invite them
morning they're already outside the door
all you have to do is say come in and
Boop okay and if you think that's not
possible
then why you want to become a Buddha
Buddhist definition can go everywhere
can help everyone can meet everyone's
mind so it's it's strange if you say I
want to become a Buddha but you believe
the Buddha's cannot read your mind to
come in the room you use something crazy
illogical right you are supposed to
become a Buddha so you can go everywhere
to help everybody before they even want
so of course the minute you invite them
they're all gonna crowd in the room okay
just tell him to stay up higher then you
don't have to clean the room okay step
I'm on it Tim oh yeah you can't eat the
offerings tonight I'm sorry fine okay
fine stock junk say suck junk do a quick
practice to clean out the worst bad days
from this week and do a quick good karma
practice
it's called cleaning and collecting good
energy cleaning bad energy collecting
everybody in this room did something
really stupid this week okay then just
remember one or two of them and clean
your heart just before you meditate then
meditate fast before you think of
another one okay all right number six
ask the ask those holy beings for help
okay and never be afraid to ask a
teacher for help just say you know I
sent my Lama I just sent him a text with
a picture of the sunset and I said help
me send me help I'm teaching classes
this mean you know some ask if you don't
ask they can't do it right
right ask for blessings for your
meditation I'm gonna meditate hey give
me some energy here I need energy give
me a shot of energy ok ask ok it's not
stupid if it's stupid you shouldn't be
here because you're supposed to be here
to become them understand ok so it never
hurts to ask all the time I'm gonna
vacuum the floor in the temple please
bless me okay just keep asking they
always agree ok no matter how stupid you
are how many bad things you did every
day they still bless you ok that's how
cool they are alright